How to measure Latency?
The process:
1) a message is written --> 
2) the producer is sending it to the kafka server --> 
3) the consumer reads the message from the server

Option 1: latency = time between 1 and  3
When the consumer consumes a message, it can record the current timestamp.
One of the fields in the consumed message is: timestamp
Therefore we can calculate:
latency = diff between current_timstamp and message_timestamp (number of milliseconds)

Option 2: latency = time between 1 and 2 --> a producer writes a message and sends it to the kafka server
We can compute the time it takes for a producer to send the message to the kafka server, I think Prometheus can help with that.
 
