1. The Throughput "Speedometer"
Query: sum(rate(messages_consumed_total[1m]))

What you learn: The total number of messages processed by your consumer per second across all partitions.

Why it’s important: This is your primary "heartbeat." If you know your producer is sending 100 packets/sec but this query shows 1.5, you have a massive performance bottleneck. It helps you find the "ceiling" of your consumer's speed.